Dare to live.
Dallas Buyers Club is a drama, history film directed by Jean-Marc Vallée.
Loosely based on the true-life tale of Ron Woodroof, a drug-taking, women-loving, homophobic
man who in 1986 was diagnosed with HIV/AIDS and given thirty days to live.
Ron Woodroof, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Eve, played by Jennifer Garner.
Rayon, played by Jared Leto.
Dr. Sevard, played by Denis O'Hare.
Tucker, played by Steve Zahn.
Richard Barkley, played by Michael O'Neill.
Dallas Buyers Club is a 2013 American biographical drama film written by Craig
Borten and Melisa Wallack, and directed by Jean-Marc Vallée.
The film tells the story of Ron Woodroof (Matthew McConaughey), a cowboy diagnosed with AIDS in the mid-1980s, a time when
both the etiology and the treatment of HIV/AIDS are poorly understood and its sufferers subject to stigma.
As part of an ongoing experimental AIDS treatment movement, Woodroof smuggles
unapproved pharmaceutical drugs into Texas to treat his symptoms.
Here, he distributes them to fellow people with AIDS by establishing the "Dallas Buyers Club",
all the while facing opposition from the Food and Drug Administration (FDA).
Two fictional supporting characters, Dr.
Eve Saks (Jennifer Garner), and Rayon (Jared Leto), were composite roles created from
interviews with transgender AIDS patients, activists, and doctors.
Presidential biographer and PEN-USA winner Bill Minutaglio wrote the
first magazine profile of the Dallas Buyers Club in 1992.
The article, which featured interviews with Woodroof and also recreated his dramatic
international exploits, attracted widespread attention from filmmakers and journalists.
Screenwriter Borten interviewed Woodroof in 1992 and wrote the script, which he polished
with writer Wallack in 2000, and then sold to producer Robbie Brenner.
Several other actors, directors, and producers were attached at various
times to the development of the film, but left the project.
Universal Pictures also tried to make the film, but did not.
A couple of screenwriters wrote drafts that were rejected.
In 2009, producer Brenner involved Matthew McConaughey because
of his Texan origins, the same as Woodroof's.
Brenner selected the first draft, written by Borten and Wallack,
for the film and then Vallée was set to direct.
Principal photography began in November 2012 in New Orleans, continuing for 25
days of filming, which also included shooting in Baton Rouge.
Brenner and Rachel Winter co-produced the film.
The official soundtrack album featured various artists, and was released
digitally on October 29, 2013, by the Relativity Music Group.
Dallas Buyers Club premiered at the 2013 Toronto International Film Festival and was released theatrically in
the United States on November 1, 2013, by Focus Features, entering wide release on November 22.
The film grossed $55 million worldwide against a $5 million budget and received
widespread critical acclaim, resulting in numerous accolades.
Critics praised the performances of McConaughey and Leto, who respectively received the Academy Award for Best Actor and the  Academy Award for Best
Supporting Actor at the 86th Academy Awards, making this the first film since Mystic River (2003), and only the fifth film ever to win both awards.
The film won the award for Best Makeup and Hairstyling and garnered nominations
for Best Picture, Best Original Screenplay, and Best Editing.
The film explores themes of aids, homophobia, rodeo, texas, biography.
The tone is emotional and intense.